Preliminary Guide to the Washington State University Facilities Planning Building Files 1979-1988
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Preliminary Guide to the Washington State University Facilities Planning Building Files
1979-1988
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
UA1992-17
Washington State University. Facilities Planning
5 Linear feet of shelf space 5 Boxes
Correspondence, memoranda, architectural contracts, and other financial and administrative reports related to several projects on the WSU campus from 1979-1988.
The Office of Facilities and Planning did not exist as a full-time staffed administrative department at WSU until 1947. Prior to this a University Architect served as the construction officer of WSU dating to 1911. Facilities and Planning was later renamed as Facilities and Development in 1993, and then as Capital Planning in 2001. The office of Facilities Operations descended from the Physical Plant in 1998, which in turn descended from Building and Grounds in 1967. While each line of programs has existed separately some migration in function has occurred over the years. The primary difference between Capital Planning and Facilities Operations is the cost of the project in question.
Primarily contains correspondence, memoranda, contract documents, and financial documents related to various projects on the WSU campus. Notable projects include the remodel of Morrill Hall, beginning sometime around 1968. Others relate to Knott Dairy Center and buildings related to the Veterinary Teaching Hospital.
This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting performed by staff.
All boxes are clearly labeled and divided by subject matter. Generally separated by date and project type as well.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This material was transferred to WSU Libraries' MASC by Lana Miller of Facilities Planning on April 23, 1992 and retained as UA1992-17.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University. Facilities Planning -- Records and correspondence
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- Miscellaneous Facilities Planning Files
  - Architect Selection, Correspondence, Notice, Advertisement, 12/1981 - 2/1988 (Box 1)
  - Asbestos Abatement # 2, 1/1986 - 9/1989 (Box 1)
  - Asbestos Meeting Materials, 3/1985 - 11/1988 (Box 1)
  - Early Start Correspondence, 12/1983 - 2/1984 (Box 1)
  - General Services (Nordquist) Correspondence, 1977 - 1978 (Box 1)
  - Graphics Exterior, 1977 - 1982 (Box 1)
  - Exterior Graphics, 1983 - 1985 (Box 1)
  - Graphics (Exterior), 1986 - 1989 (Box 1)
  - Graphics - Interior, 1980 - 1982 (Box 1)
  - Interior Graphics, 1983 - 1985 (Box 1)
  - Housing and Food Service Correspondence, 1972 - 1986 (Box 1)
  - Legal and Legislative, 1981 - 1984 (Box 1)
  - Legal and Legislative, 1985 - 1987 (Box 1)
  - Minority and Women's Business Enterprises, 12/1983 - 12/1985 (Box 1)
  - Minority and Women's Business Enterprises, 1984 - 1986 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1/1982 - 12/1982 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1983 - 1984 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1/1985 - 12/1985 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988 - 1989 (Box 2)
  - Parking, General Correspondence, 1966 - 1986 (Box 2)
  - Parking, 1987 - 1988 (Box 2)
  - Physical Plant - Litzsinger - General Correspondence, 1982 - 1986 (Box 2)
  - Physical Plant, 1987 - 1989 (Box 2)
  - President's Office - General Correspondence, 1982 - 1986 (Box 2)
  - Safety Division, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Safety Division, Rehwaldt, 1982 - 1986 (Box 2)
  - Safety Division, Correspondence, 1985 - 1986 (Box 2)
  - Staff Personnel - Meckley, Correspondence, 1979 - 1986 (Box 2)
  - Vice President Business and Finance, General Correspondence, 1982 - 1984 (Box 2)
  - Vice President Business and Finance, General Correspondence, 1985 - 1986 (Box 2)
  - Vice President Business and Finance, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Vice President Business and Finance, 1979 - 1980 (Box 3)
  - Various Small Projects in Various Bids, 1979 - 1981 (Box 3)
- Committees
  - Arboretum Committee, General Correspondence, 1987 - 1989 (Box 3)
  - Historic Preservation, 1981 - 1984 (Box 3)
  - Physical Facilities Subcommittee Minutes, 1984 - 1987 (Box 3)
- Goldsworthy Hall Building #79B
  - Goldsworthy Hall Remodel - Budget (Box 3)
  - 79B Goldsworthy Hall Renovation - Arai/Jackson, Arch and Designers, Corresp., 6/1985 - 3/1986 (Box 3)
  - Goldsworthy/Renovation, Correspondence, 3/1985 - 2/1986 (Box 3)
  - Goldsworthy Hall Remodel, Arai/Jackson, Arch and Designers, Contract, Payments (Box 3)
  - Goldsworthy Hall Renovation - Building Program (Box 3)
- Golf Course Storage Building #365B
  - Golf Course Storage Building, Budget (Box 3)
  - Golf Storage Building - Wind River Construction - Contract, Change Orders, Payments (Box 3)
  - 365B Golf Course Storage Bldg. EIS (Box 3)
  - 365B Golf Storage Facility - Dairy Reports (Box 3)
  - 365B Golf Storage Building - Wind River Construction - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - 365B Golf Storage Building - Concrete Testing (Box 3)
  - 365B Golf Storage Building - Affirmative Action Report (Box 3)
  - 365B Golf Storage Building - Mahan and Smith, Correspondence (Box 3)
  - 365B Golf Course Storage Building (Box 3)
  - 365B Golf Storage Building - Rejected Bids (Box 3)
  - Specifications for A Golf Storage Building (Box 3)
- Boiler #8, #6, Bldg. #27
  - .250 Boiler #8 Richal Smith, General Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Boiler #8, Construction Reports (Box 3)
  - Boiler #6, Repairs (Box 3)
  - New Boiler #8, General Correspondence (Box 3)
- Knott Dairy Center #402c, #402f
  - Heifer Barn - WSU Knott Dairy Center #402f - EIS - Other Correspondence (Box 3)
  - .402 Knott Dairy Center, General Correspondence (Box 3)
  - .402c Knott Dairy Center, L.C. Campbell Engineer, Contract Payments (Box 3)
- Veterinary Animal Holding Barn Building (VAHB) #169
  - VAHB # 169 Declaration of Non-Significance (Box 3)
- Veterinary Isolation Barn Building #199G
  - Veterinary Isolation Barn #199G, Declaration of Non-Significance (Box 3)
- McCoy Hall Remodeling Building # 44
  - .44 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Budget (Box 4)
  - .44 McCoy Hall (Limited) Special Procedures Room - General Correspondence, #2 11/1984 - 5/1986 (Box 4)
  - .44 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Phase II, Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare Correspondence (Box 4)
  - .44 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Ph. II, (Lmtd) Culler Gale Martell and Ericson Corresp. 6/1984 - 6/1986 (Box 4)
  - .44 McCoy Hall Room 153, Culler Gale Martell and Ericson Contract Payments (Box 4)
  - .200 McCoy Hall Remodel, Ph. I, Culler Gale Martell and Ericson Contract, C.O.'s, Estimates (Box 4)
  - .44 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Affirmative Action Reports (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Remodeling, Pittsburgh Testing (Box 4)
  - 44.250 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Richal Smith, General Correspondence, 1/1978 - 4/1979 (Box 4)
  - 44 McCoy Hall Keying Schedule (Box 4)
  - .1 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Dept. of Health Education and Welfare, Correspondence 11/1978 - 11/1981 (Box 4)
  - .44 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Diary Reports (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Remodeling, Levernier-Shea Correspondence (Box 4)
  - 44 McCoy Hall Remodel, Levernier-Shea, Construction Contract, Payments, C.O.'s 1/1980 - 3/1982 (Box 4)
  - 44 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Culler Gale Martell and Ericson Correspondence, 4/1981 - 5/1982 #4 (Box 4)
  - 44 McCoy Hall Remodeling, General Correspondence, 3/1981 - 1/1984 #3 (Box 4)
  - Rejected Bids McCoy Remodel, General (Box 4)
  - Rejected Bids McCoy Remodel, Electrical (Box 4)
  - Rejected Bids McCoy Remodel, Mechanical (Box 4)
  - Furnishings, McCoy Hall (Box 4)
  - 44 McCoy Hall Remodeling, General Correspondence, 1/1980 - 3/1981 #2 (Box 4)
  - 44.100 McCoy Hall Remodeling, General Correspondence, 6/1977 - 12/1979 (Box 4)
  - 44 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Culler Gale Martell and Ericson Correspondence, 5/1980 - 3/1981 (Box 4)
  - 44.200 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Culler Gale Martell and Ericson, General Corresp. 6/1979 - 4/1980 #2 (Box 4)
  - 44.200 McCoy Hall Remodeling, Culler Gale Martell and Ericson, General Corresp. 1/1977 - 5/1979 (Box 4)
  - Building Program For McCoy Hall Remodeling (Box 4)
- McCoy Room 153 Isolation Building #44
  - McCoy Hall Phase II (Limited), Vern W. Johnson and Sons, Inc. - Contract, C.O.'s, Payments (Box 4)
  - Budget - McCoy Hall Isolation - Room 153 (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Isolation Fac. - Pioneer Development and Construction - Contract, CO's Payments (Box 4)
  - 44. McCoy Isolation Diary Reports (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall - Room 153, General Correspondence, 11/1981 - 8/1984 (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Isolation Facility, Pioneer Development and Construction, Corresp., 10/1982 - 1/1984 (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Room 153, Culler Gale Martell and Ericson, Correspondence, 11/1981 - 1/1984 (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Isolation Facility, Rejected Bids (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall, Phase II and Isolation, Affirmative Action Reports (Box 4)
  - Building Program (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Remodeling, Phase II (Box 4)
  - Design Development Documents (Box 4)
- McCoy Hall, Phase II, Building #44
  - 44. McCoy Hall Phase II (Limited) Vern W. Johnson and Sons, Inc., Corresp. 2/1984 - 5/1985 (Box 4)
  - 44. McCoy Hall Phase II (Limited) Culler Gale Martell and Ericson, Contracts, Payments (Box 4)
  - 44. McCoy Hall Remodeling, Phase II (Limited) Diary Reports (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Remodeling Phase II Budget File - Limited Sp. Procedures Room (Box 4)
  - 44. McCoy Hall Phase II Limited Affirmative Action Reports (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Remodeling Phase II Lmtd Rejected Bids (Box 4)
  - 44. McCoy Hall Remodel. Ph. II (Lmtd) Culler Gale Martell and Ericson, Corresp. 6/1982 - 6/1984 #1 (Box 4)
  - McCoy Hall Remodeling Phase II, General Correspondence, Limited 4/1983 - 10/1984 (Box 4)
- Morrill Hall Building #24
  - Morrill Hall Remodeling Budget (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling - Affirmative Action Reports (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall Landscaping - Burke/Lee Associates, Correspondence (Box 5)
  - .250 Morrill Hall Remodeling, Richal Smith, General Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall Landscaping, Diary Reports (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling Diary Inspection Report (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling Keying Schedule (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling Meeting Minutes (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall - Landscaping EIS (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall Remodeling Landscaping, Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall Landscaping, Wind River Construction (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall Landscaping, Wind River Construction, Contract Payments (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall Remodeling, Pittsburgh Testing - Concrete Reports (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall Landscaping, Pittsburgh Testing Laboratories (Box 5)
  - Proposed Basic Health Sciences (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall, General Correspondence, 4/1/1981 - 11/18/1985 (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall .24 General Correspondence 10/1/1980 - 3/31/1981 (Box 5)
  - 24.100 Morrill Hall Remodeling, General Correspondence, 7/1974 - 9/1980 (Box 5)
  - 24. Morrill Hall Remodeling, Ralph Anderson and Partners, Correspondence 7/1/1981 - 11/4/1983 (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling, Ralph Anderson, Correspondence, 12/1/1980 - 6/30/1981 (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling, Ralph Anderson, Correspondence, 5/11/1980 - 11/30/1980 (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling, Ralph Anderson, Architect, Correspondence, 11/1/1980 - 4/30/1980 (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodel. Ralph D. Anderson and Part., Booth and Koch, General Correspondence (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodel. Ralph Anderson and Partners - Contracts, Change Orders, Payments (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodel. Ralph Anderson and Part., AIA, Contracts, Change Orders, Payments (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling, Lear Construction Co., Correspondence (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling, Lear Construction Co. #2 Contracts, Change Orders, Payments (Box 5)
  - .24 Morrill Hall Remodeling, Lear Construction Co. #1 Contracts, Change Orders, Payments (Box 5)
  - Rejected Bids - Morrill Hall - General (Box 5)
  - Rejected Bids - Morrill Hall - Electrical (Box 5)
  - Rejected Bids - Morrill Hall - Mechanical (Box 5)
  - Morrill Hall Landscaping - Rejected Bids (Box 5)
  - Program for Morrill Hall Remodeling (Box 5)